MAGNUS AGHE

206-468-6326 | magnusaghe2016@gmail.com | Houston, TX 77082 LinkedIn | GitHub | Handshake

DATA SCIENTIST|ANALYST

MS in Data Science, specializing in AI and Machine Learning, Magnus provides innovative solutions in statistical analysis, predictive modeling, and machine learning optimization. With over 16 years' industry experience, 7 in data analytics, certified in Google Data Analytics, he holds an MBA and Bachelor's in Electrical/Electronics Engineering.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

MS in Data Science, National University, CA, USA (GPA – 3.98/4.0)

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

Master of Business Administration (MBA), University of Lagos

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Ambrose Alli University

Verified International Academic Qualifications by World Education Services (WES)

March 2024 January 2022 February 2011 Nov 2004

COMPETENCIES

Machine Learning | Data Analytics | ETL | Relational Databases & SQL | Data Warehouse | Data Cleaning | Data Visualization | Data Analysis in SQL & Spreadsheets | Data Mining | R Programming | SAS | Python | SPSS | Statistics | Tableau | Pattern Recognition | Predictive Modeling | Operations Research | Project Management | Operations Management | Agile Methodologies | Scrum | Lean Six Sigma | Effective Presentations | Creative & Technical Writing | Content Writing, Dev. & Producing | Detail-oriented | Team Player | Communication

TECHNOLOGY

Statistical Tools & Operating Systems: Windows, MAC OS, Jupyter Notebook, Python, RStudio, R Markdown, Google Colab, TensorFlow, Pytorch, Keras, Orange, Excel, Google Cloud, Amazon Redshift, EC2, Amazon SageMaker, SAP HANA, Oracle, Snowflake, PowerBI, JIRA, Tableau, Looker, Plotly

Programming | Coding Languages | Collaboration Tools: Python, R, SAS, SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, BigQuery, HTML, CSS, GitHub, Kaggle, DockerHub, Microsoft Office, SAP, Salesforce, CMS, Adobe Target, ETL, SPSS, Anaconda, Jupiterian

EXPERIENCE

National University | Data Scientist | Sep 2022 - Mar 2024

Los Angeles Crime Hotspot and Category Classification (Thesis), Neural Networks and Deep Learning

- Predicted crime occurrences in Los Angeles using time series ML techniques like LSTM and ARIMA.
- Utilized ETL techniques to explore, clean, and visualize 14 years of crime and weather data.
- Performed image classification using MLP, ANN, CNN, and RNN with Keras and TensorFlow.
- Worked on classification of MNIST datasets, including Digits, Fashion and Sign Language.

Full Data Science Lifecycle Projects (including Healthcare, Financial, and Logistics Data Analysis)

- Applied ETL, data mining and machine learning algorithms using Python, R, and SAS on various datasets (e.g., Wine Quality, Fetal Health, Breast Cancer).
- Conducted A/B testing on model performance and deployed ML models to the cloud using technologies like Flask, AWS, and Docker.
- Analyzed healthcare datasets with SAS, SQL, and Tableau for pattern recognition.
- Worked on loan default classification, rental demand prediction, and predictive modeling using various machine learning techniques.

Freelancer | Business Data Analyst/Data Scientist | May 2020 - Present

- Leveraged SQL, BigQuery, and PostgreSQL to analyze large datasets using ETL techniques including from data warehousing systems like Snowflake and Oracle DBMS to enhance data-driven decision-making.
- Developed machine learning models into production environments.
- Utilized SAS, R, and Python to mine data for statistical analysis, and insightful data visualizations.
- Mastered Tableau Desktop for advanced data visualizations, business intelligence, and technical writing.
- Excelled in data analysis with Excel, with pivot tables, VLOOKUP, as well as MS Power Automate and Power BI for streamlined processes.

Amazon | Process Assistant/Data Analyst | May 2020 - Present

- Analyzed metrics using SQL. Google Sheets, Excel, performing root cause analysis, and identifying key trends.
- Developed Tableau and Power BI dashboards to monitor and report on KPIs, using ETL processes.
- Led a team of 70, optimizing workstations and maintaining high productivity and safety standards.
- Oversaw smooth operations in various process paths in the Pack Singles department.
- Spearheaded problem-solving initiatives to ensure timely package shipments, reducing CPT misses.

Ornament Media | Business Data Analyst/Content Writer | July 2017 - Feb 2020

- Drove business development and data analysis, utilizing Excel, SPSS, SAP, Oracle DBMS and PowerBI for viz.
- Grew revenue and clientele base by 600% through strategic publishing and business development initiatives.
- Authored and implemented diverse technical writing and creative content across multiple media platforms.
- Secured and executed a grant-funded radio drama series, enhancing brand visibility and outreach.

HONORS & AWARDS

- President's Circle, National University
- National Society of Leadership and Success
- Omega Nu Lambda National Honor Society, Phi Chapter

PROJECTS/PAPERS

- Advanced Crime Prediction in Los Angeles
- Microsoft Stock Price Prediction
- Seoul Bike Sharing System Demand Prediction
- Heart Disease and Heavy Alcohol Drinking Analysis

OTHER CERTIFICATIONS

Deploy and Maintain Power BI Assets and Capstone Project

Microsoft: Creative Designing in Power BI Microsoft: Data Modeling in Power BI

Microsoft: Data Analysis and Visualization with Power BI

Microsoft: ETL in Power BI

Data Warehouses

SAS Programming for R Users

Certified Business Analysis Professional (CBAP) Certification Training

Business Analytics with Excel

Tableau Desktop Certified Associate